lockergnome.com 2002-12-06

# Lockergnome's Privacy Statement

 [Book Collector](http://www.collectorz.com/book?from=lockergnome "Software for organizing your personal book collection.
Add books quickly - no typing required! Group, filter, sort and print your book list. Click for free trial version.")  
 [FirstStop WebSearch](http://www.firststopwebsearch.com/lockergnomeoffer.html "FirstStop WebSearch\(TM\) Deluxe Edition, a FREE trial version of this incredibly fast, award winning, customizable multi-search engine that has been described as the FASTEST no-nonsense meta search for the net. Now, Gnomies can save 50% when they register a copy of FirstStop WebSearch!")  

Question: which group is 250,000+ strong and always looking for stuff to make their personal and professional lives run smoother? 

**CAREER SERVICES FROM LOCKERGNOME AND DICE.COM**  
We teamed up with [Dice.com](http://seeker.dice.com/jobsearch/jobsearch.epl?rel_code=14) to bring you a full service I.T. career enhancement solution. Whether you are looking for your [dream job](http://seeker.dice.com/jobsearch/jobsearch.epl?rel_code=14) or trying to [hire talented people](http://seeker.dice.com/jobsearch/jobsearch.epl?rel_code=14), the full-featured career resource center is the place to start. Find your [IT talent solution](http://seeker.dice.com/jobsearch/jobsearch.epl?rel_code=14) today! 

©2002, Lockergnome LLC. ISSN: 1095-3965. All Rights Reserved. Please read our [Terms of Service](http://www.lockergnome.com/terms.html). Our Web site is hosted by [DigitalDaze](http://www.digitaldaze.com/?lg). Domain registered at [DNS Central](http://www.dnscentral.com/?lg). Powered by [Lyris ListManager](http://www.lyris.com/). Chris's Internet service provided by [Sonic](https://sonic.sonic.net/web_signup/submit.cgi?referrer=pirillo). 

| 

Logs

Lockergnome logs all site visits and transactions. We collect the same standard stuff: the type of browser you are using, your IP address, ISP domain, time, date, pages viewed, and length of time that you spend visiting our site. Before you start freaking out -- this data isn't used anywhere but INTERNALLY. We won't share the specifics with anybody, and we certainly don't care who you are. Well, so to speak. I mean, we CARE about you, but we don't want to match individual users with their specific Web surfing habits. 

On Lockergnome.com, we only ask for your e-mail address. You don't have to give it to us -- issues can always be viewed via the Web site. Now, in our GnomeSTORE, we will ask for your name, address, phone number, credit card number, occupation, postal code, city, state, and country -- but that's only to process your order. We collect the same information for [Gnomedex.com](http://www.gnomedex.com/) registrations. Any information collected will not leave our hands. People may ask for general numbers, but there's no way we'll give 'em specifics. We respect your right to electronic anonymity. 

IP Freely

We use a visitor's IP address to help diagnose possible problems encountered on our servers. If there is a future contention, then at least we have records on hand. An IP address may be used to gather broad demographic information; again, this information is kept internal. Honestly? We could care less where you're located on this globe, but our sponsors seem to be attracted to demographic information. Don't ask us why. Yell at them, not at us. 

Cookie Jar

If you think that turning off banners is going to make the world a better place, you're wrong. Free services aren't free to everyone. That being said, we are currently using an internal ad server to deliver targeted advertisments via the newsletter. If you catch something.lockergnome.com lingering, it's doing nothing more than offering you an image. Awwww... isn't that nice? We thought so. That I'm aware of, Lockergnome.com properties don't give you cookies. You'll have to turn to your grandmother for that kind of service. Now, from time to time, external organizations may advertise on our properties. If you wish to know who these companies are at any given time, please ask. They will vary on any given day -- depending on which programs are working better for us. Third party privacy policies are different from ours, most likely. 

If a cookie comes along, believe me -- Lockergnome isn't using it for anything and you have our permission to turn them off altogether. Sometimes we can't get paid unless indentifiers are loaded via the Web site or newsletters. These images are loaded from affiliate sites; for example, Commission Junction. 

We recently brought aboard [Burst! Media](http://www.burstmedia.com/) as an advertising partner. We're still selling sponsorships in house, but we wanted to be sure that we were maximizing our advertising space. Right now, they're doing the banners on our Web site. That frees our time up to do more important things. Like send requested information to you. 

And you may have noticed our Job search engine. It's actually not ours; it's Dice.com's, but they're partnering with us to provide you with great occupational opportunities. Understand that their privacy policy is completely separate from ours. As would be the case for any company that isn't ours. 

Subscribing Safely

Lockergnome's initial registration form requires you to give us YOUR OWN e-mail address. This is used only for the distribution of our e-mail newsletters. The personal data is never shared with an outside party, and the subscriber database is never used for purposes other than for distributing the requested newsletter(s). We do not purchase outside lists to build the subscriber databases. You must step through a confirmed opt-in procedure in order to be accepted into our warm, loving family of Gnomies. That means you have to submit a subscription request and IMMEDIATELY respond to the specially-coded message which the list server sends to the submitted e-mail address. Make sense? Okay, just type in your e-mail address, hit the Submit button, check your Inbox in a few minutes, then reply to the confirmation message to be added to the list. Easy enough? 

At any time, you may later review or update the personal information we have collected online from you by contacting us at: subscriptions@lockergnome.com. 

Unsubscribing Safely

Users may unsubscribe at any time. The databases for each list are separate. The user will need to unsubscribe from one or the other (or both) to stop receiving future mailings from our organization. To be removed from our databases, one must simply reply to a mailed issue. If that doesn't work, then he or she can flail over to the Subscriptions page. Once there, they may change or completely remove their address from our list databases. The great thing about our list software is the user can see his/her subscribed address -- if someone wishes to be removed from our list(s), we will take every step necessary to get them removed. 

The Missing Link

Our site and newsletter contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these destinations. If you wanna click, it's your choice to click. Nobody's forcing you to do anything. Of course, it won't do you much good to go through life without exploring anything new. C'mon... where's your spirit of adventure? 

You've Won

For contests, we may ask visitors for contact information and/or demographic information (postal code, occupation, or interests). The person's contact information would be used to contact him or her when e-mail does not work. What do we use this data for? Well, sometimes sponsors want to know what kind of audience our newsletter tends to attract. We only analyze group numbers -- never singling out an individual's preferences or background. Isn't that clear yet? 

If a particular contest rolls along and these policies change, we'll be sure to note it clearly on the form. 

Telling a friend

You will notice that you can 'Tell a friend about Lockergnome' on our site. Rest assured that we do not keep their e-mail address or store it in any way (if they do not subscribe, that is). The form simply sends them an invitation to join Lockergnome. IP addresses are logged and transfered only to stop possible misuse. So don't be jerkin' our chain, dude. 

Family Room

We will soon make newsgroups available to our users. Please remember that any information disclosed in this area becomes public information; one should exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information therein. Same goes for the Lockergnome chat room \-- and any other Lockergnome hosted forum. Be responsible for your own actions and words. Nobody else will. 

E-mailing Us

When you drop any of us an e-mail, we try to answer it within a 24 hour period. Unless there happens to be a problem or issue, these messages are treated as confidential. If a note must be forwarded to another party, the identifying headers are removed beforehand. 

The same holds true for every single form found on Lockergnome.com. 

Changes to this policy

If we make any changes to this policy, you will be the first to know; we'll announce any major updates in the newsletter. Again, we don’t intend on ever sharing your information with a third party; if for some reason we need to do so, you will be contacted directly and asked for your permission. But, honestly, I'd rather rip out my intestines with a fork. There, does that make you feel better? If not, please let me know why. Knowing that you're safe here. Knowing that we don't care about you in a very caring way. 

In Touch

If you have any questions about this privacy statement or the professional practices of Lockergnome, you may contact one of the head geeks, Lori Lockwood: 

108 3rd Street, Suite 305A  
Des Moines, IA 50309  
1.888.472.0483 

 Get Our Computer Tips Book!

This [compendium of Lockergnome tips](http://www.booklocker.com/books/918.html) represents just a small fraction of the information available from Lockergnome.com. Covering a range of topics, including Internet Explorer, the Windows User Interface, E-mail, Networking, Troubleshooting, and a variety of other subjects all geared toward making your computing experience both easier and more enjoyable, you'll find the [1000+ tips](http://www.booklocker.com/books/918.html) contained within these pages an invaluable resource in your personal learning process. 

Some of the tips are more technical than others, but Chris Pirillo has a gift for making even the geekiest subject accessible to virtually [any user](http://www.booklocker.com/books/918.html). Pirillo already did the work to solve your computing problems, you just have to implement his solutions. This book is available in printed or electronic format, but if you'd rather browse our collection of e-books:
